#### Contact

www.linkedin.com/in/megha-malhotra3131 (LinkedIn)

### Top Skills

C

Data Structures

Django

# Megha Malhotra

#### Software Engineer

San Francisco, California, United States

## Summary

Staff Software Engineer with 9+ years of experience in the tech industry. I have experience in delivering high-priority Business, System, and Security solutions. Mentored developers, ramping them up on new systems and delivering high-quality bug-free features. Also, have a history of contributing to all core modules by developing a deep understanding of the entire system.

## Experience

Coinbase

2 years 2 months

Staff Software Engineer April 2023 - Present (6 months)

San Francisco Bay Area

Senior Software Engineer August 2021 - March 2023 (1 year 8 months)

San Francisco Bay Area

Twitch

SDE II

October 2020 - July 2021 (10 months)

San Francisco Bay Area

Led a new project that enables qualified Music Creators to join the Twitch Affiliate Program

Worked as a tech lead with a team of developers to drive the technical design, development, and launch of the brand-new system

Built a highly available and scalable architecture in Golang using AWS Lambda, DynamoDB streams, SQS, and integrations with multiple third-party platforms

Setup alerts, monitoring, and success metrics dashboards for Observability

Tesla

Full Stack Development Intern

January 2020 - August 2020 (8 months)

Palo Alto, California

Worked on enhancements to make the Auto-diagnostic pipeline more robust and scalable for Tesla Diagnostics

Migrated the entire auto-diagnostic backend platform to Postgres from MySQL.

Owned the development, data, and infrastructure phases of the migration.

Migrated ~1M rows from MySQL to the new Postgres database

Worked on the migration of the Auto-diagnostic platform from Docker Swarm to Kubernetes and Helm.

Stack: Python, MySQL, Postgres, Splunk, Docker, Docker Swarm, Kubernetes, Helm

#### Paytm

Senior Software Engineer September 2016 - January 2019 (2 years 5 months) Noida Area, India

Managed the Supply team of Movies Vertical as a Tech Lead.

Led a team of developers and oversaw the design and delivery of critical features.

Optimized the system to reduce the latency of updates on the platform.

Used Mocha.js, Chai.js to develop testable software modules.

Delivered high-priority business and product features

Stack: Node.js, AWS, MySQL, Redis, ElasticSearch, Git

Zopper.com
Senior Software Engineer
July 2015 - September 2016 (1 year 3 months)
Noida Area, India

Owned the Zopper Assure Warranty System which offered extended warranties on electronics.

Worked on multiple modules of the Consumer Platform dealing with Order booking and delivery flow.

Mentored junior developers to ramp up on the system and deliver features. Worked on API Integration for providing a Contact Seller feature on the

Consumer side of the App.

Used Boto to save and retrieve Order Invoices on AWS

Stack: Python, Django, MySQL, Redis, AWS, Git

Microsoft Software Development Engineer June 2013 - May 2015 (2 years)

Hyderabad Area, India

I was a part of the networking team for Windows Operating System.

Contributed to shipping several updates for Windows OS. I worked on the areas including SNMP, Winsock and NSI service. As a part of the Windows team I worked on User mode and Kernel mode debugging using Windbg.

I also worked on the development of UI components in Excel for Android tablets.

Fiberlink Communications (Acquired by IBM)
Software Development Intern
January 2013 - May 2013 (5 months)

Bengaluru Area, India

The project aimed at generating e-mails to each team every day informing them of their Scheduled Tasks, Overdue Tasks, and Pending Tasks. The project was developed in

Java and made use of the DOM Parser for parsing HTML. The Mail message was generated for each user using SMTPTransport Java API.

I also worked as a part of the Localization Team in Fiberlink (Google Translate API Integration). I worked on Database Translations and UI related Bug fixes.

Stack: Java, Groovy, MySQL

## Education

IIT Roorkee

Master of Computer Applications (MCA) · (2010 - 2013)

San Jose State University

Master of Science - MS, Computer Software Engineering (2019 - 2020)

JSS Academy Of Technical Education

Bachelor of Computer Applications(BCA) · (2007 - 2010)

Somerville School, Vasundhara Enclave Delhi

## Activity

09/15/2021, Viewed by Fabio Haring

03/31/2022, Viewed by Isabelle Cruz

03/31/2022, Viewed by Christopher Chao

09/13/2023, Viewed by Joeri Leemans